Kaiji was sent to the other
room after surrendering...
カイジは星全部を
安藤と古畑に預けて
別室に墜ちた
...all the money and stars to
Ando and Furuhata.
星の売買タイムの時に
カイジに星３つを与え
They made a firm promise
to give 3 stars to Kaiji...
...during the buy-sell time
to save him.
カイジを救済するという
固い約束を交わす
だが いざその時になると…
However,
at the crucial moment...
ダメだ
この星も金も手放さない
No way!
I won't let go of both
the money and stars...
放したくない
な 何言ってんだよ
I don't want to let go!
W-What are you saying?!
We can't save
Kaiji if we do that!
それじゃカイジさんが
救えないじゃないか
かまわない
あ… 安藤！
It doesn't matter!
A... ANDO!
土壇場で拒絶 裏切り
He was rejected and betrayed
at the crucial moment!
Resurrection
何を言う 安藤
バカなこと言うな
What are you saying, Ando!
Don't say such stupid things!
そうだよ 安藤
それじゃあんまりだよ
That's right, Ando!
That's going too far!
でも そうしなきゃ
俺たちだって救われない
But if we don't do that,
we can't save ourselves either.
冷静になって よく考えてよ
Rationalise and think about it.
カイジさんを救ったら
俺たちに残るのは
If we're to save Kaiji, we'll only
have 6 million left,
３人の金を合わせた600万と
今 星を売って得た500万の
1100万だ
and the 5 million we got from
selling a star. 11 million in all.
これじゃ大アカなんだよ
We'll be deep in debt!
In fact, both Furuhata and
I borrowed...
それに船から借りた軍資金が
...2 million each
from the organisers,
俺と古畑さんが200万ずつ
カイジさんが1000万
while Kaiji borrowed 10 million,
都合1400万
which totals to 14 million!
これだけでもアカなのに
さらにこれに４割 金利がつくんだ
That's enough to be
in the red,
and there's the extra
40% interest too.
かける1.4で1960
2000万
Multiplied by 1.4, that's 19.6,
close to 20 million.
手持ちの1100じゃ全然足りない
The 11 million
we have is not enough!
900万のアカ
１人頭300万
We'll have a debt of 9 million!
Each of us will leave the ship
with a debt of 3 million.
そんな借金背負って
船から降りて
俺たち やり直せるかよ
Do you think we can
start over again with that?
古畑さん
シャバに別に借金ないの？
Furuhata, don't you have other
debts out there as well?
え？少し…
A little...
だったら分かってよ
あの人を切って星を売れば
Then please understand!
If we take him out,
we'll get a minimum of 15 million!
少なくとも あと1500は入る
手持ちの金に
それをプラスすれば 2600万
Adding to what we have,
the total amount is 26 million!
その上 カイジさんの1000万の
借金は返さなくていい
It won't matter if Kaiji
doesn't pay back his 10 million.
俺たち２人の船からの借金は
金利を含めても600程度
Your debt and mine
total 6 million in all.
つまり2600引く600で
2000万は浮く
But after repaying it, we'll
get an extra 20 million!
１人頭1000万
俺たちは1000万 持って
We'll get 10 million each...
Think about it, 10 million each.
この船から降りられるんだ
これだけあれば
シャバのケチな借金なんて帳消し
That'd definitely erase
all our debts out there.
違うか？
Am I right?
ざわ… ざわ… ざわ…
何言ってるんだ 安藤
てめえ 殺すぞ
What are you saying, Ando!
I'll kill you!
殺す 殺してやる
古畑 裏切ったらお前も殺す
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
Furuhata! If you betray me,
I'll kill you too!
フフ 恐れることはない
もう二度と あの人と
What's there to be afraid of?
We won't be seeing him again.
顔を合わせることはないからな
別室にいる連中の
この後の境遇は過酷で
It's believed that those
sent to the other room...
１年もたずに
廃人になるってうわさだ
...will meet a cruel fate and
be rendered useless soon.
すぐに俺たちの顔も忘れるさ
He'll soon forget even
our faces.
貴様… 貴様！
貴様 貴様 貴様 貴様
Why you! Why you!
Why you!
Why you!!
ぶっ殺す！
古畑 安藤を殴れ
I'll kill you!
Furuhata! Beat up Ando!
Beat him up and save me!
殴り倒して俺を救え
Save me, Furuhata!
救うんだ 古畑！
ざわ…
カイジさん ごめん
Kaiji... I'm sorry...
ごめんじゃねえ 古畑
Don't say you're sorry!
Furuhata, don't apologise!
謝ったりするな 謝るな
謝るな 古畑
Don't apologise!
Don't apologise, Furuhata!
いいな
Are you alright?
星だ
500万以上 出せる奴
Here's a star for anyone
who offers 5 million or more!
俺だ！売ってくれ
よせ よせー！
Stop it! Stop it!
The deal was made.
売買成立
やった！
Alright!
I got it! I got it!
買った 買ったぞ
買った 買ったー！
Kaiji's desire to return...
カイジの別室からの生還
その願い 計画は破綻
The realisation that all
his plans are destroyed.
残るは暗黒だけ
All that's left is
darkness...
貴様ら 貴様ら 貴様ら
Scums! Scums!
Scums!!
それでも人間か
Can you still call
yourselves human?!
ハハハハハ 捨てられて当然
It's natural to be
thrown away like that...
人間 感傷はいっとき
決断は結局 実利に流れる
We have emotions,
but in reality,
they'll always choose
the most utilitarian way.
空手では救われるわけがない
It's only normal that
a poor man like you...
当たり前のこと
...won't be saved.
カイジくん
Kaiji...
ありがとう
ありがとうございます
Thank you...
Thank you very much!
必ず… 必ず救い出しますから
We'll surely...
We'll surely save you!
遠いはずだ あの時
Of course it felt as if
they were faraway.
I should have realised it
at that time!
奴らの声を遠く感じて当然
奴らにすれば あの時点で
俺の命など どうでもいいこと
I didn't mean anything to them
right from the start.
あの涙は いっときの感傷
決意なき涙
Those tears were just
momentary emotions...
腹の底じゃ もう冷酷に
切る算段を始めていた
They were just
crocodile tears!
安藤は100パーセントそう
Ando must have planned
that from the start.
古畑も無意識下で
その作業をしていた
Furuhata followed the
plan without thinking about it...
だから遠く感じたんだ
That's why it
felt so insincere...
あの遠さは
奴らの声に現実味が
That distance was
evident in their voices.
本気で俺を救おうという意思
ぬくもりがなかったんだ
They never really had the
intention to save me!
It's too late to
realise that now, Kaiji.
気づくのが遅かったな カイジ
友情や口約束でもらえるのは
Friendships only give you memories
and empty promises...
旅先からの絵はがきや土産
あるいは思い出というガラクタ
そんな程度のもの
...that amount to
nothing at all.
本当に肝心なものは
There's no way that
the friendship...
...will become something
great.
決して友情なんかでは
譲られない
利しかないのさ
It has no value!
この世で本当に欲しいものや
地位を手に入れようとしたら
If you really want to gain
status or possessions,
you'll need money!
Nothing works but money!
金！金しかない
結局 お前ら２人は
その当たり前の認識が甘かった
Both of you are too naive
to know about the real world.
俺は そのことについてだけは
シビアだったから
I paid a lot of attention to that,
こうして生き残れる　まあ
hence I've been able to survive...
Well, do your best to comfort
each other from now on.
あとは せいぜい２人で
慰め合って生きていくんだな
金？救われるには
Money?
I need money to be saved?
金…
Money?
利…
Benefits!
この時 カイジにあるひらめき
At that moment,
Kaiji had a flash of inspiration!
カイジくん？
Kaiji?
おい
Hey!
貴様 何をする
離れんか
What are you doing?!
Get off him!
よせ
死ぬぞ
Stop it!
He'll die! Let him go!
離さんか
この このガキが
You stupid punk!
いい加減にしろ
You should
know your place!
このガキ！
You brat!
Let him go!
離せ おい
お前も さっさと出ろ
金持って
Get out of here now!
And take your money with you!
You dumb brat!
このくそガキ
見苦しいわ
上がれんのは お前の甘さ
Don't you have any sense?!
You're unable to
get out of here...
うかつさからだ
それを いくらねたましいからって
...because you
weren't paying attention!
And you're taking it out on me
just because of envy?!
俺に八つ当たりするとは何事だ
クズが
You piece of trash!
You're done for!
Die! Die! Die!
死ね 死ね 死ね
お前はもう終わりだ
It's the end for you!
生きても あと２～３年
死ね 死にさらせ
You'll have only 2 to
3 years to live! Die!
Go and die!
カイジくん
Kaiji...
どうして… こんなことをしても
何の得にもならないのに
Why? Nothing will come out
of doing such things...
そりゃ あの男の口様は
悔しいっていうか
It's true that
his words were vexing,
腹立たしかったけど
これから先のことを考えたら
and it makes you mad...
But thinking of
what's ahead of us,
無茶はいけない
we can't be careless!
特に黒服の人への暴力は
心証ってものがあるんだから
Especially with the guys
in black suits around,
it'll reflect badly on us...
おとなしくしているのが一番
It's best to obedient.
暴れて いいことはひとつもない
Nothing good will come
from doing this.
フッ フフッ そうでもないさ
It's nothing like that.
じたばたすることで開ける
Only by making
a last ditch struggle...
そんな活路 逆転 生還
...can it be opened.
The path to survival...
is to struggle.
そう 生還がある
There's still a chance
to stay alive!
まだ
I won't...
諦めねえ 最後まで
I won't give up!
Not until the very end!
そんな…
諦めないと言ったって
Just because you
don't want to give up?
どう考えたって 生還なんて
This is not how
you should survive...
へへへ それが
そうでもねえのさ
You are wrong.
奴が口にしてただろ
He was talking about it,
wasn't he?
ここから引き上げてもらおうと
思ったら
If you want to be saved
from here,
俺みたいに金を抱いて墜ちるか
either be like me and come here
holding on to money,
シャバに強力なお宝でも
隠しておいて
or hide something valuable
in the outside world...
助けざるを得ないという
状況しかない
That's the only way to make sure
that you'll be saved.
奴が大事に抱えていた
あの大金は
The treasure that he was
taking good care of...
...is cash.
そういう意味の金
だとすると足りないよな かなり
Which is far
from enough.
だって
The cash that
he was holding on to...
奴が持っていた金は
せいぜい700～800万
...was at most 7-8 million.
これじゃあ星３つ使って
救い出す価値なんてない
It's not worth using
3 stars to save him.
１つ500万で
取り引きされてるんだから
Since each star is
being traded for 5 million,
最低 1500万は抱いて
墜ちなきゃ救われない
he had to be holding
at least 15 million.
てことは もう１つの保証
This means that he has
another guarantee.
シャバに隠しておいたお宝
He's hidden a great treasure worth
tens of millions out there...
うん千万って額は
くだらない大金
そのありかを
岡林だけが知っている
And only Okabayashi
knows where it is.
だが仲間に隠し場所が
バレちまったら それまで
But, if the place was known,
あっさり裏切られる
he would be easily betrayed.
100パーセント 仲間にバレぬよう
現金を隠しきるのは難しい
It's hard to
hide cash without...
...letting your comrades
know where it is.
Which means that
the safest way...
となると 一番安心なのは
そのお宝を手に墜ちることだ
...is to bring it with you
when you come here.
つまり うん千万っていう現金を
In other words, he converted the
money into precious jewels.
小さな宝石とか貴金属に換え
それを手に墜ちるしかない
He had to do that
when he came here.
But still...
でも私たちは その…
We are... well...
as you can see,
このとおり 丸裸で
we're naked...
石田さん 覚えてるか？これ
Ishida...
Do you remember this?
うっ それって…
Does that mean...?!
That's right...
そうさ 奴の背中のばんそうこう
The bandage on his back!
じゃあ まさか…
Then, don't tell me that...?
おい 例のやつ
- Where is it?
- Yeah, it's here.
ああ ここにあるぜ
おい ないぞ
Hey! It's gone!
ざわ… ざわ…
そうさ
That's right...!
今頃 気づいたか まぬけめ
You've noticed it only now,
you blockhead?
Who's the one not paying
attention now? Okabayashi! Idiot!
ぬけてんのは貴様なんだよ
大甘さ バカめ
貴様 貴様 貴様！
Darn it! Darn it!
何だ これは
どういうことだ
What's going on?!
What's the meaning of this?!
ど… ど どうって…
Well, well...
このバカ カス ゴミ クズ！
こいつ
You idiot! You piece of trash!
Garbage! Useless!
カイジくん
Kaiji...
Hey, save me!
さあ 救え　この宝石に
1500万以上の価値があるなら
If these are worth
15 million or more,
救わざるを得まい
you'll have to save me!
さっさと救え ゴミども
Hurry up and save me,
you pieces of trash!
星 売買の残り時間 ３分
3 minutes left for
the trading of stars!
結局 岡林たちのグループは
しかたなくカイジを指名
Finally,
Okabayashi and gang...
...had no choice
but to select Kaiji.
カイジが どさくさに紛れて
かすめた宝石は
Kaiji had made use of the
chaotic situation...
2000万の価値があった
...to grab the jewels that's worth
20 million to save his life!
救わざるを得ない
See you...
じゃあな
カイジくん
Kaiji...
カイジくん…
こんなことが…
こんな逆転が起こるなんて
How could such a thing...
How could such
a reversal happen?
こんな地の果ての
穴蔵みたいなところでも
In a place that's like an abyss,
こんな逆転が…
he pulled off
such a reversal...
諦めなければ
If I hadn't given up...
諦めさえしなければ…
If only I hadn't given up...!
おらおら 700 700
Come on, come on!
7 million, 7 million!
隠してる金 全部出すんだ
Hand over all the money
you're hiding!
ケチケチしてると買い損ねるぞ
If you're too stingy,
you'll miss the chance to get one!
あ 安藤
A-Ando...
カ カイジさんが消えた
Kaiji...
he's disappeared...
That's impossible.
そんなことあるかよ
もう望みがないから奥にでも…
He must've lost all hope
and went further in...
ざわ… ざわ… ざわ…
バ バカな！
ど… どうして？
I-Impossible!
How did he?!
カイジ！貴様
Kaiji! You!
ああ… カ カイジさん
そ その…
K-Kaiji! Well...
Stop, stop it!
The devil made me do it!
よして ま 魔が差したんだ
ちょっと ほんのちょっとだけ
I lost my senses! Really!
やめようって
僕はギリギリまで その…
Please stop it. Up till
the last moment, I was...
欲かいて
俺を抹殺しようとした奴が
You guys tried to kill me
for your greed,
今さら何を言う
so what are you talking
about?!
てめえらみたいな裏切り者の
I don't talk to betrayers,
腐れきった最低な奴とは
口もききたくねえ
lowlifes that don't deserve to live!
黙って今持ってる
薄汚ねえ星と金を
Shut up and hand over
all the dirty money...
全部出せ
...and stars that you have!
Oh, Kaiji!
カイジさん
出せ
Hand them over!
金もだ
全部ですか？
The cash as well!
All of it?!
当たり前だ！
Of course!
カイジさん ひどいっすよ
Kaiji!
That's too much!
最後はともかく
俺たちは途中まで
Apart from the end,
weren't all of us comrades?
仲間だったじゃないっすか
そうっすよ
That's right!
いわばその金は
みんなで協力してつくった金
So that money...
...was due to everyone's effort!
それを全部はひどい
To hand it all over is
too much!
カイジさんだけ得するなんて
そうっすよ
Only you will
benefit from this!
That's right!
俺らにも取り分くださいよ
Please give us our share as well!
いい加減にしろ！ゴミどもが
That's enough,
you pieces of trash!
捨ててやる こんな金
す 捨てるって？
I'll throw this money away!
Throw away...?!
うんざりだ
もううんざりだ
I've had enough!
I've had more
than enough!
うんざりだ うんざりだ
ヘドが出る
I've had enough! Enough!
I want to throw up!
売って 売ってくれ！
Sell it to me!
Sell it to me please!
I only have 4 million now,
今は400しかないけど
船から降りたら
but I'll definitely pay you
another 3 million later!
必ず300は上乗せするから
バカ野郎
信じられるか そんな話
You idiot, how can I
believe such a thing?
It's true! Even if I don't have
it now, my parents will pay you!
本当だ
俺に金はなくても親が出す
親が必ず出す
そんなこと言うなら
My parents
will surely pay!
If that's the case, my parents
will pay 7 or 8 million too!
俺の親だって出す
700や800万
俺も
俺も親が出す
Me too!
My parents will pay!
親だと？
Your parents?!
黙れ！そんなクズに売るな
Shut up!
Don't sell it to them!
キャッシュで800万
俺が買う
8 million in cash!
I'll buy it!
カ カイジさん
何をバカなことを
K-Kaiji?! How can you do
such a stupid thing?!
今さら星を買っても
What's the point
of buying stars now?!
売った！
Sold!
めちゃくちゃ
It's all messed up...
これで あの男を救ってくれ
I want to use these stars
to save that man.
カイジくん ありがとう
Kaiji...
Thank you so much!
ど どうして こんなおっさんを？
Why him?!
資産でもあるの？
Does he have
lots of property?!
ひょっとして こう見えても
シャバにすごい資産が…
Does he have great wealth
out there despite his looks?
Idiot, of course he doesn't.
バカ あるわけねえだろ
スカンピンだ 俺たちと同じさ
He's completely broke,
just like us!
カイジさん 勘弁してくださいよ
Kaiji!
Give us a break!
それじゃあ…
黙れ
Then why?
Shut up!
言ったろ 捨てるって
うんざりなんだよ
I said I'd throw it away!
I've had enough!
損だ 得だ 金だ 資産だ
そんな話はもう
Losses, gains,
money, possessions.
I've had enough of that!
そんなことを話せば話すほど
俺たちは あさましく
The more we talk about it,
the worse it's going to get.
醜く はい回ってることになるんだ
Miserable and unsightly!
この地獄の釜の底をな
Here in this insufferable
place!
Don't you understand that?!
それが分かんねえのか？
And the organisers are
having fun by watching us!
そして そんな姿を見て
主催者が喜ぶ
その互いにおとしめ合う
仕組みを考えた
Those scoundrels
are smirking away...
...as we plot
against each other!
ブタ野郎がほくそ笑む
The more we get caught up
in winning and losing,
俺たちが損得に振り回されれば
振り回されるほど
血道を上げれば上げるほど
the more engrossed
we become.
And that's exactly what
those garbage want!
結果的に
そのゲス野郎の思うつぼ
Don't you feel vexed?!
悔しくねえのか？
悔しくねえのかよ！
くそ！くそ くそ くそ
Darn it!
Darn it, darn it,
darn it!
くそー！
Darn it!
くそ くそー！
ああ くそー！
Darn it!!
楽しい
This is enjoyable...
いや 楽しめそうな男じゃないか
No, it seems like
I can get a lot of...
...enjoyment from this man.
Darn it! Darn it!
Darn it!
くそ くそ くそ
くそ野郎！
Darn it!!
こうしてカイジたちの長い夜
With the end of 4 hours
of plots and schemes,
Kaiji's long night finally
draws to a close.
狂気と策略が交差する
４時間あまりが終わった
参加者103名のうち 36名が
36 out of the 103 participants
on board the Espoir...
エスポワールにのみ込まれ
地獄へ墜ちた
...didn't make the cut and
were met with a cruel fate.
そして かろうじて
生還できた者は67名
And only 67 barely
made it out alive.
しかし その多くはシャバの借金は
チャラになったものの
Although most of them
had their debts...
...from the outside world erased,
船で また新たな借金を背負い
they incurred fresh debts
from the ship,
街へ戻ることになる
and returned to the streets...
ざわ… ざわ…
ざわ…
次回 ｢使者｣
Next, Messenger.